Hello, everyone, and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name's Erica.
我是Erica。
And I'm Marco.
我是Marco。
So, Marco, how are you doing today?
那么，Marco，你今天怎么样？
I'm great.
我很好。
I'm really happy to be back, ready to deliver another great podcast for all our listeners.
我很高兴回来，准备为所有听众带来另一期精彩的播客。
That's right.
没错。
And we've got an intermediate lesson today about spending money.
今天我们有一节关于花钱的中级课程。
Yeah, specifically spending money in a company.
是的，具体来说是在公司里花钱。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to be listening to a business meeting as a company describes how they're
我们将听到一个商务会议，一家公司在描述他们如何
spending money.
花钱。
Right.
对。
And they're actually looking at their profit and loss statement.
他们实际上正在查看他们的损益表。
So that's kind of interesting.
这还挺有意思的。
Well, Marco, can you tell us a little bit about a profit and loss statement?
那么，Marco，你能给我们讲讲损益表吗？
Yeah, sure.
当然可以。
Well, all companies come out with a profit and loss statement every year or every three
嗯，所有公司每年或每三个月都会出一份损益表。
months.
And it's basically a document that shows all the money that the company is spending and
它基本上是一份显示公司所有支出和
all the money that the company is earning.
所有收入的文件。
So it's a document that outlines how much money the company makes and how much it spends.
所以这是一份概述公司赚了多少钱、花了多少钱的文件。
Right.
对。
So in the end, basically, it'll tell you we're making money or we're losing money.
所以最终，它会告诉你我们是在赚钱还是在亏钱。
Okay.
好的。
So we're going to be listening to some people discuss a profit and loss statement in just
我们马上就会听到一些人讨论损益表。
a moment.
But before we do that, it's time for vocabulary preview.
但在那之前，是词汇预览时间。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
So today on our vocabulary preview, we have two words for you.
今天在词汇预览中，我们有两个单词要介绍。
So let's take a look at the first one.
让我们看看第一个。
Expenses.
Expenses。
So expenses are things that you have to spend money on regularly.
Expenses是指你必须定期花钱的东西。
Right.
对。
So for example, in a company, regular company expenses are salaries or office supplies or
例如，在公司里，常规的公司支出包括工资、办公用品、
the phone bills, internet bills.
电话费、网费等。
Okay.
好的。
Maybe in a household or a family, your expenses might be your food, perhaps your transportation
也许在一个家庭里，你的开支可能包括食物、交通
or your rent or your heating bill.
或者房租、暖气费。
So these are all things you spend money on regularly.
这些都是你定期花钱的地方。
They're expenses.
它们就是开支。
Expenses.
开支。
Great.
很好。
Let's take a look at our second word.
我们来看第二个词。
Through the roof.
高得离谱。
So when something is through the roof, it's...
所以当某样东西高得离谱时，它意味着……
Really really really really high.
非常非常非常高。
Really high.
非常高。
So for example, we can talk about gas prices are through the roof lately.
比如，我们可以说最近油价高得离谱。
Yeah, that's totally true.
是啊，确实如此。
Gas prices have gone really high in the past couple of months.
过去几个月油价涨得很高。
So when we talk about through the roof, it means that the number is really high.
所以当我们说高得离谱时，意思是数字非常高。
That's right.
没错。
We typically use this word with numbers.
我们通常用这个词来形容数字。
It also gives you the idea that the number has risen really quickly.
它也表示数字涨得非常快。
Yeah, exactly.
对，完全正确。
Okay.
好的。
So through the roof.
所以是高得离谱。
Through the roof.
高得离谱。
All right, Marco, do you think it's time for the dialogue?
好了，Marco，你觉得该听对话了吗？
Yep, let's listen to the dialogue.
是的，我们来听对话吧。
As always, the first dialogue is going to be a little bit fast, so it might be a little
和往常一样，第一遍对话会有点快，所以可能有点
bit difficult, but...
难懂，但是……
Don't worry if you don't understand everything, because we will explain all of the key language
如果没全听懂也别担心，因为我们马上会解释所有关键语言点。
in a minute.
好的。
Okay, so now the last point on our agenda.
那么，现在是我们议程上的最后一点。
Jill, let's go over the profit and loss statement.
Jill，我们来看一下损益表。
Great.
好的。
Well, the main issue here, as you can see, is that our expenses are through the roof.
嗯，主要问题在于，正如你所见，我们的开支高得离谱。
Let's see.
让我看看。
These numbers are off the charts.
这些数字高得离谱。
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事？
Well, sir, the company expenditures on entertainment and travel are out of control.
先生，公司在娱乐和差旅上的支出失控了。
Look at these bills, for example.
比如看看这些账单。
Just this month, we've paid over $20,000 for hotel charges.
就这个月，我们已经付了超过两万美元的酒店费用。
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'll look into it.
我会查一下的。
The list goes on and on.
这样的账单还有很多。
Here, this is a bill for $5,000 for spa treatment.
这里，这是一张五千美元的水疗账单。
Thank you.
谢谢。
That will be all.
就这些了。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
Look at this one, sir.
先生，看看这个。
$5,000 were expensed in one night at a place called Wild Things?
一晚上在“野东西”这个地方花了五千美元？
Okay, I get it.
好吧，我明白了。
Thank you for your very thorough analysis.
感谢你非常详尽的分析。
Okay, so this accountant, she's pretty thorough, hey?
好吧，这个会计挺细致的，是吧？
She's really persistent about her job, and the manager apparently is a little bit embarrassed.
她对工作真的很执着，而经理显然有点尴尬。
I wonder why that could be.
我想知道为什么会这样。
Well, we'll talk about that in a little while.
嗯，我们一会儿再谈这个。
Why don't we take a look at our language takeaway for today?
不如我们来看看今天的语言点？
Language takeaway.
语言点。
In today's language takeaway, we're going to look at three words, and the first word
在今天的语言点中，我们要看三个词，第一个词
is expenditures.
是 expenditures。
Expenditures.
Expenditures。
So expenditures sounds pretty close to expenses, right?
所以 expenditures 听起来和 expenses 很像，对吧？
It's pretty similar, but it has a little bit of a difference.
它们很相似，但有一点区别。
So why don't we listen to some examples and see if we can understand?
那我们听一些例子，看看能不能理解？
Example one.
例子一。
If elected president, I will increase expenditures on health and education by 12%.
如果当选总统，我将把医疗和教育支出增加12%。
Example two.
例子二。
We really need to control our travel expenditures.
我们真的需要控制差旅支出。
From now on, all managers will fly economy class.
从现在开始，所有经理都将乘坐经济舱。
Example three.
例子三。
Because of the rise in oil prices, expenditures on food are higher than they have ever been.
由于油价上涨，食品支出比以往任何时候都高。
So expenditures is the total amount of money that you're spending on something.
所以 expenditures 是你花在某件事上的总金额。
Right.
对。
That's the total amount of money versus expenses is the things that you spend money on.
那是总金额，而 expenses 是你花钱的具体项目。
Okay, that's really clear.
好的，这很清楚。
Our next word is out of control.
我们的下一个词是 out of control。
Out of control.
失控了。
So when something is out of control, it's crazy.
所以当某件事失控时，就是很疯狂。
You can't control it.
你无法控制它。
Exactly.
没错。
You can't stop it.
你无法阻止它。
Out of control.
失控了。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
Now, let's take a look at our last word for today.
现在，我们来看看今天的最后一个词。
Go over.
Go over。
So go over is a pretty simple word.
Go over 是一个很简单的词。
Why don't we listen to some examples so we can understand go over?
我们不如听一些例子来理解 go over？
Example one.
例子一。
I need to go over this report one last time to make sure there are no mistakes.
我需要最后检查一遍这份报告，确保没有错误。
Example two.
例子二。
Can you help me go over my presentation?
你能帮我检查一下我的演示文稿吗？
I want to make sure it's perfect.
我想确保它完美无缺。
Example three.
例子三。
Let's go over these numbers one more time and make sure there are no mistakes.
我们再仔细看一遍这些数字，确保没有错误。
Yeah, this is a really common word and it basically means look at carefully.
是的，这是一个很常见的词，基本上意思是仔细查看。
Yeah, or review.
是的，或者复习。
In English, we often find simple little words, they fit together really well.
在英语中，我们经常发现简单的小词，它们搭配得很好。
And you think, oh, they're so easy, like the word go over, so easy.
你会想，哦，它们太简单了，比如 go over 这个词，太简单了。
Yeah.
是的。
But it's the way that they interact with each other that makes them...
但正是它们之间的互动方式让它们……
Or it makes you sound much better.
或者说让你听起来更地道。
Exactly.
没错。
So go over, in this case, we might say, let's go over the lesson.
所以 go over，在这种情况下，我们可以说，让我们复习一下这节课。
Let's go over the lesson.
让我们复习一下这节课。
Yeah, that sounds great.
是的，听起来不错。
Yeah, and that's a more natural way of saying something like that.
是的，这样说更自然。
Okay, so we've taken a look at our language takeaways for today.
好了，我们已经看完了今天的语言要点。
I think it's time to listen to the dialogue one more time.
我想是时候再听一遍对话了。
And this time, the dialogue will be slower so we can understand and listen to all the
这次对话会慢一些，这样我们就能听懂并听到所有
words we just talked about.
我们刚刚讨论过的词。
Okay, so now the last point on our agenda.
好的，现在是我们议程上的最后一点。
Jill, let's go over the profit and loss statement.
吉尔，我们来仔细看一下损益表。
Great.
太好了。
Well, the main issue here, as you can see, is that our expenses are through the roof.
嗯，主要问题在于，你看，我们的开支高得离谱。
Let's see.
让我看看。
These numbers are off the charts.
这些数字高得离谱。
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事？
Well, um, sir, the company expenditures on entertainment and travel are out of control.
嗯，呃，先生，公司在娱乐和差旅上的支出失控了。
Look at these bills, for example.
比如看看这些账单。
Just this month, we've paid over $20,000 for hotel charges.
就这个月，我们已经支付了超过两万美元的酒店费用。
Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
I'll look into it.
我会调查一下。
The list goes on and on.
这样的例子还有很多。
Here, this is a bill for $5,000 for spa treatments.
这里，这是一张五千美元的水疗账单。
Thank you.
谢谢。
That will be all.
就这些了。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
Look at this one, sir.
先生，看看这个。
$5,000 were expensed in one night at a place called Wild Things?
一晚上在“野性”这个地方花了五千美元？
Okay, I get it.
好了，我明白了。
Thank you for your very thorough analysis.
感谢你非常详尽的分析。
Okay, so I got it.
好的，我懂了。
Yeah, it's clear now.
是的，现在清楚了。
Yeah, and you know, I heard a lot of really great phrases in this dialogue that I'd like
是的，而且我听到这个对话中有很多非常好的短语，我想
to look at now in Fluency Builder.
在流利度训练中看一下。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Great.
太好了。
So today on Fluency Builder, we have three words for you.
今天在流利度训练中，我们准备了三个词。
Let's start by looking at the first one, off the charts.
我们先看第一个，off the charts。
Off the charts.
Off the charts。
So this word is very similar to through the roof.
这个词和 through the roof 很相似。
Exactly.
没错。
It also means really high.
它也意味着非常高。
Right.
对。
So let's listen to some examples of how we can use off the charts in a different situation.
我们来听一些例子，看看如何在不同情境下使用 off the charts。
Example one.
例子一。
Oil prices have gone up and our costs are off the charts.
油价上涨，我们的成本高得离谱。
Example two.
例子二。
Excellent job, Susan.
干得好，苏珊。
Your sales are off the charts this year.
你今年的销售额高得惊人。
Example three.
例子三。
Our losses are off the charts.
我们的损失高得离谱。
That's it.
就这样。
No losses for anyone.
没有人有损失。
So Marco, do you think I can change off the charts for through the roof in these examples?
那么马可，你觉得在这些例子中我能不能把“off the charts”换成“through the roof”？
Yeah, you can.
是的，可以。
Definitely.
当然可以。
You can use off the charts or through the roof.
你可以用“off the charts”或“through the roof”。
Both of them mean the same thing.
它们俩意思一样。
Okay.
好的。
So two ways of saying really, really, really high.
所以有两种方式来表达非常非常非常高。
Really high.
非常高。
But they're very commonly used in a business setting.
但它们在商务场合中非常常用。
Yeah, that's true.
是的，没错。
Okay.
好的。
So this next word is a phrase that you can use if you want to tell somebody that you'll
所以下一个词是一个短语，如果你想告诉某人你会
check something or you'll investigate something.
检查某事或调查某事，就可以用这个短语。
Right.
对。
And we heard it in our dialogue.
我们在对话中听到了它。
So let's listen to the clip.
那么我们来听一下这段录音。
I'll look into it.
我会查一下的。
So look into that.
所以查一下那个。
That means I'll check something.
那意思是我会检查某事。
Yeah, I'll see what's happening.
是的，我会看看发生了什么。
Yeah.
嗯。
Does it mean you're going to take action?
这是不是意味着你要采取行动？
No, it doesn't.
不，不是。
Okay.
好的。
So I think we've got another word that does mean you're going to take action.
所以我觉得我们有另一个词确实意味着你要采取行动。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
So this word means that you're going to do something about it.
所以这个词的意思是你会对此采取行动。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
I will take responsibility.
我会负责的。
Exactly.
没错。
So I will do something about it.
所以我会对此采取行动。
I will investigate and I'll do it.
我会调查并去做。
Yeah.
是的。
Again, two great phrases.
又是两个很棒的短语。
I'll look into it.
我会查一下的。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
Okay.
好的。
So now let's listen to the dialogue a third time.
现在让我们第三次听对话。
It's going to be at its normal speed, but now you have all the tools you need to understand
这次是正常语速，但你现在已经掌握了所有需要理解的工具，
it a lot better.
能更好地理解它了。
Okay.
好的。
So now the last point on our agenda.
那么现在议程上的最后一点。
Jill, let's go over the profit and loss statement.
吉尔，我们来看一下损益表。
Great.
好的。
Well, the main issue here, as you can see, is that our expenses are through the roof.
嗯，主要问题在于，正如你所见，我们的开支高得离谱。
Let's see.
让我看看。
These numbers are off the charts.
这些数字高得离谱。
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事？
Well, sir, the company expenditures on entertainment and travel are out of control.
先生，公司在娱乐和差旅上的支出失控了。
Look at these bills, for example.
看看这些账单，比如这个。
Just this month, we've paid over $20,000 for hotel charges.
仅这个月，我们就支付了超过两万美元的酒店费用。
Okay.
好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'll look into it.
我会查一下的。
The list goes on and on.
这样的例子还有很多。
Here, this is a bill for $5,000 for spa treatment.
这里，这是一张五千美元的水疗账单。
Thank you.
谢谢。
That will be all.
就这些了。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
Look at this one, sir.
先生，看看这个。
$8,000 were expensed in one night at a place called Wild Things.
在一个叫“野性之物”的地方，一晚就报销了八千美元。
Okay.
好的。
I get it.
我明白了。
I'll do a very thorough analysis.
我会做一个非常彻底的分析。
Marco, I guess one of the benefits of being an executive in a company, especially a large
马可，我想作为公司高管的好处之一，尤其是在大公司，
company, is you get a lot of amazing benefits.
就是你能得到很多优厚的福利。
Yes.
是的。
When you are a manager or a CEO of one of these big companies, you get a lot of great
当你成为这些大公司的经理或CEO时，你会得到很多好东西，
things like, I don't know, a private jet maybe.
比如，嗯，私人飞机之类的。
Well, that's nice.
那挺好的。
Or the company often pays for your house.
或者公司经常为你支付房子费用。
Yeah.
是啊。
Or for your car, they'll give you a company car.
或者给你配一辆公司车。
They'll pay for your kids' or your children's tuition for high school.
他们还会为你孩子的中学学费买单。
So there are school fees.
所以有学费。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Also, I've heard about entertainment bonuses.
另外，我听说过娱乐津贴。
Yeah.
是的。
So you can go out to a restaurant, get the receipt, and claim the expenses at work.
所以你可以去餐馆，拿到收据，然后向公司报销费用。
Those are some great benefits, right?
这些福利很不错，对吧？
So Marco, I'm curious to know what our listeners' expenses are.
那么Marco，我很好奇我们的听众都有哪些开销。
Yes.
是的。
We definitely want to know what crazy expenses you have.
我们很想知道你们有哪些疯狂的开销。
For example?
比如呢？
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我想想。
My spending on Coke Zero has gone through the roof since we started this podcast.
自从我们开始这个播客以来，我在零度可乐上的花费就飙升了。
Yes.
是的。
You spend a lot of money on Coke Zeros every week, right?
你每周在零度可乐上花很多钱，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
I probably have about, I don't know, 10 a week.
我大概每周喝10罐，我也不确定。
Well, for example, I spend a lot on DVDs each week.
嗯，比如我每周在DVD上花很多钱。
I usually buy two or three movies.
我通常买两三部电影。
That is off the charts.
那真是高得离谱。
That is off the charts for DVD spending.
在DVD花费上真是高得离谱。
So we want to know what you spend your money on.
所以我们想知道你们把钱花在什么地方。
Be sure to go into our community website and tell us what you spend money on.
一定要去我们的社区网站告诉我们你花钱的地方。
That's right.
没错。
You can find us at EnglishPod.com.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
And Marco and I are always there to respond to your questions and comments.
我和Marco随时在那里回答你们的问题和评论。
Great.
太好了。
So we'll see you there.
那我们到时候见。
And until then, it's goodbye.
在那之前，再见。
Goodbye.
再见。